scworks.org 2018-09-01

# SC Works - Bringing Employers and Job Seekers Together

Thank you for visiting this South Carolina Department of Employment and Workforce (DEW) web site. DEW is committed to preserving your privacy when you visit DEW websites. This privacy statement addresses the collection, security and disclosure of information that may be obtained through the use of websites maintained by DEW.

**COLLECTION OF INFORMATION**  
If you visit a website maintained by the South Carolina Department of Employment and Workforce in order to read or download information, we may collect the following information:

The name of your domain; for example, "abzcompany.com";  
The IP address of the client accessing the web site; a number automatically assigned to your computer when you are using the Internet;  
The type of browser and operating system used to access DEW sites;  
The Internet address of the website from which you linked directly to DEW sites;  
The pages you visit within DEW website(s); and  
The links made to other websites through DEW sites.

This information is collected for purposes of determining what information is of most and least interest to all visitors and in improving content and performance of the web site. This information is not collected for commercial marketing purposes.

DEW may collect personally identifiable information that you voluntarily provide while visiting an DEW maintained web site. Examples of personally identifiable information may include (but are not limited to):  
An e-mail address, if you are communicating with us through e-mail;   
Information you voluntarily submit to DEW for the purposes of completing or submitting an application or form online; and   
Other information volunteered, such as vendor profile/contact information, survey information or content of e-mail.

In general, please note the information collected, whether personally identifiable, is not limited to text characters and may include audio, video and other graphic formats you send us. Information is retained in accordance with existing laws, rules, regulations, and other policies.

**USE OF COOKIES**  
DEW web applications may create "cookies" to hold user information.  These "cookies" are then sent to, and stored on, the user's computer.  This information is handled in the same way as other personally identifiable information obtained by us.  No user information will be gathered through the use of "cookies" except that which is required to run the specific application(s) being accessed by the user.

**USE OF CONSTITUENT E-MAIL ADDRESSES**  
E-mail addresses obtained as a result of requests to DEW web sites will not be sold or given to any organization for marketing purposes. The information collected is subject to the access and confidentiality provisions of the State's Freedom of Information Act and other applicable sections of the South Carolina Code of Laws and/or federal law. E-mail or other information requests sent to DEW web sites may be maintained in order to: respond to the request, forward that request to the appropriate department or agency, communicate updates to the system that may be of interest to citizens, or provide DEW web developers with valuable customer feedback to assist in improving the site.

**DATA SECURITY AND QUALITY**  
DEW is committed to data security and the data quality of personally identifiable information that is either available from, or collected by, DEW web sites, and has taken precautions to protect personally identifiable information from loss, misuse or alteration. Any third parties responsible for this information are committed to the same principles, and also are required by contract to follow the same policies and guidelines as the State of South Carolina in protecting this information. Unless otherwise prohibited by state or federal law, rule or regulation, individuals will be given the ability to access and correct personally identifiable information maintained by us that may be in error.

**PUBLIC DISCLOSURE**  
As a general rule, DEW does not disclose any personally identifiable information collected online except where permission has been granted, or where the information is public information under the South Carolina Freedom of Information Act or other applicable laws. Information collected pursuant to the South Carolina Employment Security Law is also protected from disclosure by the confidentiality provisions S.C. Code Ann. Sections 41-29-160 et seq. Visitors should be aware that information collected by DEW on its websites may be subject to inspection, if such information is a public record or not otherwise protected from disclosure.  
The Family Privacy Protection Act of 2002, S. C. Code Ann. Sections 30-2-10 through 30-2-50, prohibits persons or private entities from using any personal information obtained from DEW’s web sites for commercial solicitation purposes. A person knowingly violating this prohibition is guilty of a misdemeanor and subject to the penalties specified in Section 30-2-50 (D).

**LINK DISCLAIMER**  
Websites maintained by DEW may contain links to other websites, including those owned or maintained by other government, private, or not-for-profit entities. Such links are provided for convenience and/or information purposes only. A link does not constitute an endorsement of content, viewpoint, policies, products or services of that website. Once you link to a website not maintained by DEW, you are subject to the terms and conditions of that web site, including but not limited to its privacy policy. 

**INFORMATION DISCLAIMER**  
Information provided on web sites maintained by DEW is intended to allow the public convenient access to public information. While all attempts are made to provide accurate, current and reliable information, we cannot guarantee that the information will be error-free. Therefore, DEW and respective employees, officers and agencies expressly deny any guarantee of the accuracy, reliability or timeliness of any information published through DEW web sites and shall not be held liable for any losses caused by reliance upon the accuracy, reliability or timeliness of such information.

Any person, who relies upon such information obtained from these websites, does so at his or her own risk.  
The contents of this website are published for information purposes only and subject to change without notice.
